Finding Aid for Jens Jensen Drawings and Papers 1903-1951
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Drawings
  - Chicago Parks
    - Chicago Parks
      - Planting plan for players green. Columbus Park. West Chicago Parks, 1918; CHI-PARKS37; Ink on linen; location, type of plantings; notes; unsigned; 58 x 84 cm; Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
        (neg. # CHI-PARKS37)
      - Rock work for the wading pool at Columbus Park, 1920; CHI-PARKS38; Orange, green, red, black pencil on tracing paper; plan, cross section; signed; 32 x 50 cm; Scale: 1"" = 10' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
        (neg. # CHI-PARKS38)
      - A topo. survey of Cragin Park site, Northwest Park District, 1921; CHI-PARKS39; Brown, black ink on linen; topo. lines, elevations; signed; 100 x 65 cm; Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - A grading plan showing water and drainage system. Cragin Park, Northwest Park District, 1921; CHI-PARKS40; Red, yellow, brown, black ink on linen; contour lines, tile locations, pools, tennis courts; signed; 100 x 65 cm; Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - A planting plan. Cragin park, Northwest Park District, 1921; CHI-PARKS41; Yellow, black ink on linen; location, type, amounts of plantings; tennis courts, pools, footpaths, campfires; signed; 100 x 65 cm; Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - Sections showing grades. Cragin Park, Northwest Park District, 1921; CHI-PARKS42; Ink on linen; five sections; signed; 100 x 49 cm; Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - Plan showing electric light and water pipe lines. Cragin Park, Northwest Park District, 1921; CHI-PARKS43; Brown, black ink on linen; signed; 100 x 65 cm; Scale: 1"" = 20' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - Special Parks Commission. Crescent Park in Edgebrook, 1909; CHI-PARKS44; Ink on linen; location, type of plantings; signed; 54 x 60 cm; Scale: 1"" = 50' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - Landscape design and planting plan. Dauphin Park. Special Park Commissioners, CHI-PARKS45; Ink, pencil on linen; location, type of plantings; unsigned; 67 x 42 cm (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - Design of Douglas Park gardens showing changes in planting arrangements, 1909; CHI-PARKS46; Ink on linen; location, type of plantings; pools, seats; signed; 104 x 41 cm; No scale (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - General plan for Marshall Blvd. entrance to Douglas Park for West Chicago Park Commissioners, 1910; CHI-PARKS47; Red, black ink on tracing paper; plans, sections, elevations; signed; 92 x 62 cm; Scales vary (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - Detail of steps for arbor at Marshall Blvd. entrance to Douglas Park. West Chicago Park Commissioners, 1910; CHI-PARKS48; Red, black ink on tracing paper; plan, section; signed; 51 x 30 cm; Scales vary (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - Working plans for construction of posts for arbor at Marshall Blvd. entrance to Douglas Park for West Chicago Park Commissioners, 1910; CHI-PARKS49; Red, black ink on tracing paper; plans, elevations, details; signed; 83 x 55 cm; Scales vary (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - Design for terra cotta vases. Entrance to garden at Douglas Park. Design for flower boxes. Marshall Blvd. entrance, 1910; CHI-PARKS50; Red, black ink on linen; signed; 56 x 28 cm; Scale (for flower boxes): 1"" = 1' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - Design of concrete seat for arbor. Marshall Blvd. entrance to Douglas Park. Chicago. West Park Commission, 1910; CHI-PARKS51; Red, black ink on linen; plan, elevations, sections; signed; 31 x 33 cm; Scale: 1"" = 1' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - Planting plan for entrance to Douglas Park, 1910; CHI-PARKS52; Red, black ink on linen; location, type of plantings; pools; seats; signed; 59 x 52 cm; Scale: 1"" = 16' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - Planting plan. Douglas Park garden, 1910; CHI-PARKS53; Ink on linen; location, type of plantings; pool; signed; 63 x 32 cm; Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - Planting plan for southern part of Douglas Park, 1910; CHI-PARKS54; Ink on linen; location, type, amounts of plantings; pools, athletic fields; signed; 106 x 103 cm; Scale: 1"" = 50' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - No Title, CHI-PARKS55; pencil, blue, green, brown watercolor on tracing paper; plan, elevations for entrance to park, with columns, pools; unsigned; 94 x 73 cm (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - No Title, CHI-PARKS56; pencil, red, black ink on tracing paper; content similar to CHI-PARKS55; 'Douglas Park"" on verso; unsigned (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - Plat of East End Park showing trees and surface elevations, 1906; CHI-PARKS57; Red, blue, yellow, black ink on linen; elevations, distances; location, type of trees; 54 x 76 cm; Scale: 1"" = 40' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - Planting plan. East End Park, CHI-PARKS58; Ink on linen; location, type of plantings; unsigned; 72 x 46 cm; Scale: 1"" = 40' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - West Chicago Park Commissioners. B.A. Eckhart Park, 1912; CHI-PARKS59; Blueline print on heavy paper; plan of grounds, with field house, library, halls, pools, playgrounds; unsigned; 75 x 85 cm; Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 48, Folder 17)
      - Planting design of Ellis Park. Special Park Commissioners - Chicago, 1907; CHI-PARKS60; Ink on linen; location, type of plantings; pools; signed; 44 x 59 cm; Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Design for Frankline Park. West Chicago Park Commission, 1914; CHI-PARKS61; Blueprint; plantings, pools, play areas, field house; unsigned; 70 x 80 cm; Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Partial planting plan. Franklin Park, 1915; CHI-PARKS62; Pencil on tracing paper; location, type of plantings; unsigned; 42 x 35 cm; Scale: 1"" = 30' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Planting plan for Franklin Park, 1916; CHI-PARKS63; Pencil on tracing paper; location, type of plantings; pools, plyfields; signed; 68 x 71 cm; Scale: 1""= 50' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Planting plan of formal garden for Garfield Park, 1907; CHI-PARKS64; Blueline print copy; original signed; 70 x 80 cm; Scale: 1"" = 50' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Planting plan of Garfield Park, 1907; CHI-PARKS65; Blueline print; location, type, amounts of plantings; original signed; 135 x 84 cm.; Scale 1""=50' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Proposed design of palm house. New conservatory at Garfield Park, CHI-PARKS66; Blueline print; topo lines, elevations within building; original signed; 97 x 53 cm.; Scale: 1/8"" = 1' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - [no title], CHI-PARKS67; Blueline print; plan of grounds, with buildings, trails, plantings; unsigned; 93 x 75 cm.; no scale (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Finerty Monument. Garfield Park. Survey of location, CHI-PARKS68; Pencil on tracing paper; location of trees, monument; unsigned; 56 x 37 cm.; Scale: 1""=20' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Setting for Finerty Monument. Garfield Park, CHI-PARKS69; Pencil on tracing paper; location, type of plantings; signed; 37 x 19 cm.; Scale: 1""=20' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - [no title], CHI-PARKS70; Pencil, red, black ink on tracing paper; present, proposed roadways, traffic circle; at lower right, ""Garfield Park""; unsigned; 72 x 62 cm.; no scale (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - [no title], CHI-PARKS71; Pencil, ink on tracing paper; similar to 62, with street names; unsigned; 30 x 36 cm.; Scale 1""=50' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Revised preliminary plan for Grant Park, 1903; CHI-PARKS72; Brownline print; plan of buildings, monuments, plantings; executed by ""Olmsted Brothers, Landscape Architects, Brookline, Mass.""; 66 x 38 cm.; Scale: 1""=300' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Untitled, 1903; CHI-PARKS73; 1903?; pencil sketch on tracing paper, ink on linen drawing; plan of grounds, with buildings, pools, footpaths, gardens; unsigned; 90 x 34 cm.; no scale (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Untitled, 1903; CHI-PARKS74; 1903?; pencil sketch on tracing paper, ink on linen drawing; plan of grounds, with buildings, pools, footpaths, gardens; unsigned; 90 x 34 cm.; no scale (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Preliminary sketch for play ground. West Chicago Park Commissioners, 1912; CHI-PARKS75; Pencil, blue, green, purple, red watercolor on tracing paper; plan of grounds, with pools, playing areas, buildings; signed; 35 x 39 cm.; Scale 1""=50' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Preliminary sketch for play ground. W. Chicago Park Comm. Harrison Pk., 1912; CHI-PARKS76; Pencil, blue, green, purple, orange watercolor on tracing paper; layout different from 64; signed; 38 x 37 cm.; Scale 1""=50' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Harrison Park. West Chicago Park Comm. Park No. 6, 1913; CHI-PARKS77; Blueline print on heavy paper; notes in pencil on changes in plantings; signed in pencil; 65 x 67 cm.; Scale 1""=30' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Preliminary sketch for changes in Harrison Park., 1915; CHI-PARKS78; Blue, green, orange, red, black pencil on tracing paper; location of buildings, walks, plantings; cross-section; signed; 33 x 43 cm.; Scale 1""=30' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - West Chicago Park Commissioners. Harrison Park, 1918; CHI-PARKS79; Blackline print; plan of grounds; unsigned; 20 x 25 cm.; Scale: 1""=100' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - No title, CHI-PARKS80; Blue, green, orange, red, black pencil on tracing paper; plan of pools, buildings, etc.; overleaf with square play field pasted over circular playfield; at lower right, ""Harrison Pk.""; (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Harrison Pk, CHI-PARKS81; Pencil on tracing paper; note at lower left, ""Not original copy""; similar to 67; notes; unsigned; 37 x 39 cm.; Scale: 1""=50' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Preliminary sketch. Holstein Playground. West Chicago Park Comm., 1911; CHi-PARKS82; Pencil, green, red, purple watercolor on tracing paper; location of buildings, facilities, plantings; signed; 44 x 31 cm.; no scale (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Proposed planting plan of the west part of Humboldt park, 1907; CHI-PARKS83; Blueline print; location, type, amount of plantings; original signed; 77 x 90 cm.; Scale: 1""=20' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - No title, CHI-PARKS84; Red, black ink on linen; plan, details, elevations of drinking fountain; on verso, ""Drinking fountain, Humboldt Pk""; unsigned; 95 x 100 cm.; Scales vary (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Sketch for subway under Humboldt Park, 1908; CHI-PARKS85; Pencil, green, orange watercolor on tracing paper; location of subway, entrances, plantings; signed; 130 x 35 cm.; Scale 1""=50' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Planting plan for Merrick Park, 1906; CHI-PARKS86; Ink on linen; location, type, amounts of plantings; key to plantings, facilities; signed; 60 x 34 cm.; Scale 1""=40' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Planting design of block 3. Norwood Park. Special Park Commissioners, 1906; CHI-PARKS87; Ink on linen; location, type of plantings; signed; 30 x 24 cm.; Scale: 1""=40' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Planting design of block 10. Norwood Park. Special Park Commissioners., 1906; CHI-PARKS88; Ink on linen; location, type of plantings; signed; 31 x 43 cm.; Scale: 1""=40' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Proposed change and planting plan of public park at Norwood Park. Special Park Commission, CHI-PARKS89; Ink on linen; location, type of plantings; walkways, fountain, rail depot; key to plantings; signed; 62 x 38 cm.; Scale: 1""=40' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Park IV, CHI-PARKS90; Pencil on tracing paper; location of buildings, plantings, pools; unsigned; 64 x 55 cm.; Scale: 1""=30' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Preliminary sketch for recreation center. West Chicago Park Com. Sketch No.1, 1911; CHI-PARKS91; Blue ink, blue, green, red, purple watercolor on tracing paper; pools, buildings, plantings; at bottom, ""Pulaski Pk.""; signed; 63 x 36 cm.; Scale: 1""=30' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Preliminary sketch for recreation center. West Chicago Park Comm. Sketch no.2, CHI-PARKS92; Pencil, blue ink, blue, green, red, purple watercolor on tracing paper; notes; cross-section at bottom; at top, ""Pulaski Pk.""; signed; 60 x 38 cm.; Scale: 1""=30' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Sketch for recreation centre. West Chicago Park Comm., 1912; CHI-PARKS93; Ink, blue, green, orange, pink, black pencil on tracing paper; pools, gardens, playfields, buildings; at bottom, ""Pulaski Pk.""; unsigned; 59 x 34 cm. (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Revised sketch for the play field. Park no. 5 [?] W. Ch. Pk. Comm, CHI-PARKS94; Pencil, on tracing paper; location of plantings, arbors, seats; at right, ""Pulaski Pk""; signed; 27 x 28 cm.; Scale: 1""=30' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Preliminary sketch for [torn away] and [illegible]. Quarry [torn away] West Chic[torn away], 1912; CHI-PARKS95; Pencil, blue, green, purple watercolor on tracing paper; pool, plantings, playing fields; note; at bottom, ""Quarry Pk""; signed; approx. 60 x 38 cm.; No scale (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Special Park Commission. Sayre and Rutherford Park at Mont Clare..., 1909; CHI-PARKS96; Ink on linen; location, type of plantings, pool revised in pencil; signed; 84 x 66 cm.; Scale: 1""=40' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - West Chicago Park Commissioners. Sheridan Park, 1913; CHI-PARKS97; Blueline print; plan of buildings, pool, playgrounds; unsigned; 67 x 51 cm.; Scale 1""=30' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Union Park. West Chicago Park Commissioners. Chicago...Planting plan, 1914; CHI-PARKS98; Blueline print--green, brown, blue ink on heavy paper; pools, plantings, drains, walkways; types of trees; note by date, ""received Mch 5th, 1915. EL.""; unsigned; 53 x 57 cm.; Scale: 1""=50' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Sketch plan. Outdoor baths and childrens playground in the N.W. corner. Union Park, CHI-PARKS99; Blue, green, yellow, pink, black pencil on tracing paper; location of buildings, pools, walks, playing fields; unsigned; 58 x 55 cm.; Scale: 1""=50' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - A preliminary sketch for the redevelopment of Vernon Park. West Parks, 1917; CHI-PARKS100; Pencil and blue pencil on tracing paper; location of walks, plantings, building; elevation of building; signed; 87 x 26 cm.; Scale: 1""=40' (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
      - Maps of the parks under the jurisdiction of West Chicago Park Commissioners, 1912; CHI-PARKS101; Folder enclosing six sheets; maps of Garfield, Douglas, Humboldt, Union, Wicker, Vernon, Holstein, and Parks no. 2, 3, 5; unsigned (Map-case 48, Folder 18)
  - Chicago. Sanitary District-Curtis
    - Chicago. Sanitary District.
      - Untitled, 1909; CHI-SAN1; 1909?-1923?; Green, yellow ink on blueline print; plan of area bordering slough; unsigned; 48 x 89 cm.; No scale (Map-case 48, Folder 15)
      - Untitled, 1909; CHI-SAN2; 1909?-1923?; Green brown ink on blueline; area bordering slough from Lawrence to Touhy Ave.; unsigned; 35 x 200 cm.; no scale (Map-case 48, Folder 15)
    - Chicago. Street Improvements.
      - No title, 1903; CHI-STR1; Baring Ave.; Ink on linen; plantings along sections of three streets: Baring Ave, Olcott Ave, Tod Ave.; lists of tree and shrub types; cross-sections; signed; 170 x 88 cm.; Scale: 1""=50' (Map-case 48, Folder 15)
      - Plan for improving Division St., west of Mozart St., 1909; CHI-STR2; Red, black ink on linen; location of plantings; on verso, ""West Pks""; signed; 77 x 19 cm.; Scale: 1""=50' (Map-case 48, Folder 15)
      - No title, CHI-STR3; [Humboldt entrance]; Red, black ink on linen; elevation of gateway to street; note, ""Imprvt Division St.""; unsigned; 70 x 29 cm.; No scale (Map-case 48, Folder 15)
      - No title, CHI-STR4; Ink on linen; three sections of plantings along portions of Humboldt Blvd.; unsigned; 72 x 50 cm.; No scale (Map-case 48, Folder 15)
      - A sketch for west entrance of Jackson Boul. West Chicago Park Commission, 1920; CHI-STR5; Pencil on tracing paper; plan of entrance; signed; 140 x 32 cm.; Scale: 1""=20' (Map-case 48, Folder 15)
      - No title, CHI-STR6; Pencil on tracing paper; sketch of entrance to Jackson Blvd.; unsigned; 53 x 45 cm.; No scale (Map-case 48, Folder 15)
      - No title, 1905; CHI-STR7; Ink on linen; plan of roadway between North Ave. and Palmer Square; note at bottom with date and initials ""J.K.""; unsigned; 47 x 136 cm.; No scale (Map-case 48, Folder 15)
      - No title, CHI-STR8; Ink on linen; plantings along sections of three streets: Northcote Ave., 143rd St., Prentiss Ave.; cross-sections (Map-case 48, Folder 15)
    - Chicago Technical University (proposed)
      - Proposed Chicago Technical University Agricultural High School, 1919; CHI-TEC1; Colored pencil on tracing paper; buildings, gardens, pools, signed; 135 x 65 cm.; Scale: 1""=100' (Map-case 48, Folder 15)
        (neg. # CHI-TEC1)
      - Proposed Chicago Technical University, 1919; CHI-TEC2; Ink on linen, indicates location of buildings, playing fields, pools, gardens, vegetation, signed; 140 x 65 cm.; Scale: 1""=100' (Map-case 48, Folder 15)
        (neg. # CHI-TEC2)
    - Churchill, Arthur, Burlington, Iowa
      - Plat of Arthur Churchill's grounds on Prospect Hill...showing location of residence, tennis court, and trees, 1915; CHU1; Ink on linen, with topographical lines and [...missing] (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - Plat of Arthur Churchill's grounds on Prospect Hill...showing location of residence, tennis courts, and trees, 1915; CHU2; Blue ink, black, green pencil; numerous additions, corrections of plantings, pool, courts; unsigned; 49 x 46 cm.; Scale: 1""=20' (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - A planting plan for the estate of Arthur Churchill, Prospect Hill, 1915; CHU3; Ink on linen, indicates location and type of plantings; signed; 90 x 50 cm.; Scale: 1""=20' (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
    - Clark, J.M., Freeport, Illinois
      - Untitled, 1924; CLA1; Ink on tracing paper; survey of property; unsigned; 52 x 19 cm. (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - A planting plan for the estate of Mr. J. M. Clark, 1925; CLA2; Ink on linen, indicates location and type of plantings with cross-section detail of pool; signed; 99 x 40 cm.; Scale: 1""=20' (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - A revised planting plan for a portion of the estate of Mr. J. M. Clark, 1925; CLA3; Ink on linen, indicates location and type of plantings for area around residence; signed; 95 x 44 cm.; Scale: 1""=10' (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - Construction plan of pool. Estate of Mr. J. M. Clark, 1925; CLA4; Ink on linen, with cross-sections and ground plans of pool (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
    - Clark, Kenneth D., Glencoe, Illinois (Ralph A. Stoetzel, architect)
      - Proposed ... residence for Mr. and Mrs. K. D. Clark, 1925; CLC1; Blueprint; elevation of front of residence; Ralph E. Stoetzel, architect; unsigned; 42 x 27 cm.; Scale: [1/8""=1'] (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - Proposed ... residence for Mr. and Mrs. K. D. Clark ... first floor plan, 1925; CLC2; Blueprint; Ralph E. Stoetzel, architect; unsigned; 33 x 32 cm.; Scale: 1/8""=1' (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - Proposed ... residence for Mr. and Mrs. K. D. Clark ... second floor plan, 1925; CLC3; Blueprint; Ralph E. Stoetzel, architect; unsigned; 40 x 31 cm. (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - Proposed ... residence for Mr. and Mrs. K. D. Clark ... Valley Road elevation, 1925; CLC4; Blueprint; Ralph E. Stoetzel, architect; unsigned; 42 x 26 cm.; Scale: 1/8""=1' (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - Proposed ... residence for Mr. and Mrs. K. D. Clark, 1925; CLC5; Blueprint; elevation; unsigned; 42 x 22 cm.; Scale: 1/8""=1' (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - Survey for Mr. and Mrs. Kenneth D. Clark, 1926; CLC6; Pencil on tracing paper; Ralph E. Stoetzel, architect; plantings, walks sketched; unsigned (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - Mr. and Mrs. K. D. Clark, 1927; CLC7; Blueprint; plan of grounds with plantings, walks; original signed; 43 x 50 cm.; Scale: 1""=10' (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
    - Clarke, Harley L., Evanston, Illinois and Lake Geneva, Wisconsin (Richard Powers, architect)
      - A topographical plan of the estate of Mr. Harley L. Clarke, 1922; CLE1; Ink on linen, with topographical lines and elevation; unsigned; 135 x 40 cm.; Scale: 1""=20' (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - A planting plan for the estate of Mr. Harley L. Clarke, 1922; CLE2; Ink on linen, indicates location, type and amount of plantings; unsigned (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - Preliminary ground plan B, showing location of house and gardens...Mrs. H. L. Clarke, 1926; CLE3; Blueline print, green, black pencil; sketch revisions of driveway, building; unsigned; 60 x 77 cm.; Scale: 1/16""=1' (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - House ... for Mr. H. L. Clarke ... plot plan, 1926; CLE4; Blueprint; Richard Powers, architect; unsigned; 102 x 56 cm.; Scale: 1/16""=1' (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - House ... for Mr. H. L. Clarke .. Plot plan, 1926; CLE5; Blueprint, pencil; some tree marked with pencil; Richard Powers, architect; unsigned; 104 x 65 cm. (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - House...for Mr. H. L. Clarke .. First floor plan, 1926; CLE6; Blueprint, pencil; pencil revisions, notes; Richard Powers, architect; unsigned; 104 x 78 cm.; Scale: 1/4""=1' (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - House ... for Mr. H. L. Clarke .. First floor plan, 1926; CLE7; Blueprint; Richard Powers, architect; unsigned; 75 x 43 cm. (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - A planting plan for the estate of Mr. Harley L. Clarke, 1928; CLE8; Ink on linen, indicates location, type and amount of plantings; signed (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - A planting plan for the estate of Mr. Harley L. Clarke, 1928; CLE8a; Blackline print, indicates location, type and amount of plantings; signed (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
      - A plan of the watering system. Mr. Harley L. Clarke, CLE9; Ink on linen; unsigned; 138 x 77 cm.; Scale: 1""=10' (Map-case 49, Folder 19)
    - Clow, Henry B., Lake Forest, Illinois (Marshall & Ford, architect)
      - Topographical survey for grounds of Mr. Henry B. Clow, 1910; CLO1; Pencil, red, black ink on linen; topo lins, elevations; residence, driveways, gardens in pencil; signed; 116 x 42 cm.; Scale: 1""=50' (Map-case 49, Folder 20)
      - Mr. H. B. Clow ... Preliminary sketch for the gardens. No. 1, 1910; CLO2; 4 sheets, pencil and watercolor on tracing paper; signed (Map-case 49, Folder 20)
      - Mr. H. B. Clow ... Preliminary sketch for the gardens. No. 2, 1910; CLO2; 4 sheets, pencil and watercolor on tracing paper; signed (Map-case 49, Folder 20)
      - Mr. H. B. Clow ... Preliminary sketch for the gardens. No. 3, 1910; CLO3; 4 sheets, pencil and watercolor on tracing paper; signed (Map-case 49, Folder 20)
      - Mr. H. B. Clow ... Preliminary sketch for the gardens. No. 4, 1910; CLO4; 4 sheets, pencil and watercolor on tracing paper; signed (Map-case 49, Folder 20)
      - Mr. H. B. Clow ... Preliminary sketch for the gardens. No. 5, 1910; CLO5; 4 sheets, pencil and watercolor on tracing paper; signed (Map-case 49, Folder 20)
      - Plan of drives, drains and electric light conduit, grounds of Mr. H. B. Clow, 1910; CLO6; Pencil, ink on linen; signed; 114 x 42 cm.; Scale: 1""=50' (Map-case 49, Folder 20)
        (neg. # JEN-Clo-6)
      - Plan of waterpipes. Grounds of Mr. H. B. Clow, 1910; CLO7; Pencil, ink on linen; signed; 116 x 42 cm.; Scale: 1""=50' (Map-case 49, Folder 20)
        (neg. # JEN-Clo-7)
      - Design of bridge and retaining wall for grounds of Mr. Harry B. Clow, 1910; CLO8; Red and black ink on tracing paper, with cross-sections, elevations and ground... (Map-case 49, Folder 20)
      - Design, showing reinforcement, for East Bridge for grounds of Mr. Harry B. Clow, 1910; CLO9; Red and black ink on tracing paper, with ground plan, elevations and cross-section; signed; 97 x 70 cm.; Scale: 1/2""=1' (Map-case 49, Folder 20)